1. ArrayList is a class, that uses a dynamic array for storing the elements. It is an implementation of List , backed by an array. 
All optional operations including adding, removing, and replacing elements are supported.Unlike an Array you do not have to provide an initial size. 
This means we can keep on adding to an ArrayList without worrying about the size of your list. So an Array is static where as an ArrayList is dynamic.
One can also easily create object collections of your defined classes with the ArrayList syntax. Eg.:
ArrayList<ObjectType> list = new ArrayList<>();



2. An iterator is used to cycle through the elements in a collection,, obtaining or removing elements.
 ListIterator extends Iterator to allow bidirectional traversal of a list, and the modification of elements.
Iterator in Java is nothing but a traversing object, made specifically for Collection objects like List and Set.
Java iterator is an interface belongs to collection framework allow us to traverse the collection and access the data element of collection without bothering the user about specific implementation of that collection it. 
Basically List and set collection provides the iterator. You can get Iterator from ArrayList, LinkedList,etc.



3.The important points about Java ArrayList class are:
-->Java ArrayList class can contain duplicate elements.
-->Java ArrayList class maintains insertion order.
-->Java ArrayList class is non synchronized.
-->Java ArrayList allows random access because array works at the index basis.
-->In Java ArrayList class, manipulation is slow because a lot of shifting needs to be occurred if any element is removed from the array list.



4.Advantages :
a.You can define ArrayList as re-sizable array. Size of the ArrayList is not fixed. ArrayList can grow and shrink dynamically unlike arrays which are of fixed length.
b. Elements can be inserted at or deleted from a particular position.
c.ArrayList class has many methods to manipulate the stored objects like add,remove,etc.
d.ArrayList can hold any type of objects.
e.We can traverse an ArrayList in both the directions – forward and backward using ListIterator.



5.Any instrument which collects values and stores them. I could be a computer, a sensor or even a program.



6.A linked list is a linear collection of data elements, called nodes, each pointing to the next node by means of a pointer. 
It is a data structure consisting of a group of nodes which together represent a sequence. A linked list is a sequence of data structures, which are connected together via links.
-->Link − Each link of a linked list can store a data called an element.
-->Next − Each link of a linked list contains a link to the next link called Next.
-->LinkedList − A Linked List contains the connection link to the first link called First.



7.The java.util.LinkedList.listIterator(int index) method returns a list-iterator of the elements in this list (in proper sequence), starting at the specified position in the list.
Following are the basic operations supported by a list.
-->Insertion − Adds an element at the beginning of the list.
-->Deletion − Deletes an element at the beginning of the list.
-->Display − Displays the complete list.
-->Search − Searches an element using the given key.
-->Delete − Deletes an element using the given key.


8.Java LinkedList class uses doubly linked list to store the elements. It provides a linked-list data structure. It inherits the AbstractList class and implements List and Deque interfaces.
-->Java LinkedList class can contain duplicate elements.
-->Java LinkedList class maintains insertion order.
-->Java LinkedList class is non synchronized.
-->In Java LinkedList class, manipulation is fast because no shifting needs to be occurred.
-->Java LinkedList class can be used as list, stack or queue.



9.They are the following:
-->Linked lists are a dynamic data structure, which can grow and be pruned, allocating and deallocating memory while the program is running.
-->Insertion and deletion node operations are easily implemented in a linked list.
-->Dynamic data structures such as stacks and queues can be implemented using a linked list.
-->There is no need to define an initial size for a linked list.
-->Items can be added or removed from the middle of list.



10.It can be used for web browser and to develop stacks and queues.


11. Differences:
a.LinkedList and ArrayList are two different implementations of the List interface. LinkedList implements it with a doubly-linked list. 
ArrayList implements it with a dynamically re-sizing array.
b.LinkedList<E> allows for constant-time insertions or removals using iterators, but only sequential access of elements. 
In other words, you can walk the list forwards or backwards, but finding a position in the list takes time proportional to the size of the list.
ArrayList<E>, on the other hand, allow fast random read access, so you can grab any element in constant time. But adding or removing from anywhere but the end requires shifting all the latter elements over, either to make an opening or fill the gap
c.ArrayList class can act as a list only because it implements List only.LinkedList class can act as a list and queue both because it implements List and Deque interfaces.
