1. A function is a group of statements that together perform a task.It is a collection of statements that are grouped together to perform an operation.
Syntax: 
public static int methodName(int a, int b) 
{
 body
}

Here: public is a MODIFIER - defines the access type of the method and it is optional to use.
int is RETURN TYPE - Method may return a value.Method may return a value. Incase, it doesn't it is void.
methodName  is the function name/method name - The method signature consists of the method name and the parameter list.
a, b are parameters - It is the type, order, and number of parameters of a method. These are optional.
method body − The method body defines what the method does with the statements.

2.The mechanism used to pass parameters to a procedure (subroutine) or function. 
The most common methods are to pass the value of the actual parameter (call by value), or to pass the address of the memory location where the actual parameter is stored (call by reference). 
Eg.: add(int a, int b)
{
some statements
}

public static void main(String[] args) 
{
  add(12,15); //calling method add
  .............
}
 
3. void is a Java keyword.
Used at method declaration and definition to specify that the method does not return any type, the method returns void.

4. 'args' contains the command-line arguments passed to the Java program upon invocation.String[] args is an array of strings passed into main as parameters.
It's a String because the command line is expressed in text. 
Also, no one knows what the programmer will use. For this reason, with the 'args[]' of type String you can pass N arguments to you program, and convert as you need, because a String can become whatever primitive type in Java.


